Manuel Jiménez

CRA 56 # 161 - 71 TO 1 AP 601 • Bogotá, Colombia

CELL (+57) 310-884-7675 • E-MAIL man.jime@gmail.com • LINKEDIN https://www.linkedin.com/in/manjime/

PROFILE **Systems Engineer** with 15+ years Systems Engineer able to properly meet the requirements of systematic processes for any business or institution.

Ability to develop software in various programming languages. Knowledge of management information systems for planning and management of an organization.

Excellent interpersonal skills, with ability to work in teams. Leadership ability and desire to constant improvement. Adaptability to change and continuous learning.

COMPETENCIES Team worker.

Capacity to manage stress and stressful situations.

Strong Object Oriented skills: Analysis, Design and programming.

Experience with: NodeJS and TypeScript, Java 11, EE4J 7, XML, HTML, SQL, CSS, SOAP/REST services, PHP, C++, C. **IBM Cloud:** IBM Integration Bus v10, IBM DataPower Gateway, IBM WebSphere Service Registry and Repository,

IBM Business Process Manager, IBM Transformation Extender, IBM WebSphere Integration Developer

Application Servers: Glassfish, Tomcat, JBoss, WebSphere Liberty

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, DB2, and some NoSQL experience

Development tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Maven and version control systems like SVN, GIT

Operative Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)

Languages: English and Spanish.

CLOUD EXPERIENCE: Design and implementation of solutions based on cloud architectures, supported under AWS and IBM Cloud solutions in several sectors of the industry. Use of deployment mechanism in cloud based on containers, such as Docker, Docker-Compose and Kubernetes, under ECS and EKS platforms. Deployment of projects using CloudFormation, CloudFoundry, Node.js and Java, supported on a model of DevOps-based deployments. Publishing of REST services supported by API Connect. Configuration of hybrid environments, combined Cloud solutions and On-Premise solutions. Use of serverless functions based on Lambda and OpenWisk. Design of banking applications making use of BlockChain for the development of safe applications, to give value to the solutions supporting us on this technology. Enthusiast in IoT solutions, C development, Arduino Libraries, Raspberry Pi and Node-RED. Use of platforms for device visualization, use of different communication protocols such as MQTT, ZigBee, GRPS, and management of different sensors, GPS, RFID, NFC. Integration of cognitive solutions such as Chatbots, image recognition systems, personality analysis from social networks.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (September 2019)

IBM Certified Advanced Application Developer - Cloud Platform V1 (September 2018)

IBM Certified Architect - Cloud Solutions v3 (August 2018)

CORDA r3 Corda Certified Developer (Jun 2018)

IBM Certified Solution Developer - Integration Bus v10.0 (May 2018)

IBM Certified Solution Implementer - DataPower Gateway v7.6 (March 2018)

https://www.youracclaim.com/users/manuel.jimenez

EXPERIENCE

Cloud and Hybrid Integration Architect – AOS SAS. (November 2018 to date)

Lead the cloud adoption of the company, motivating and giving guidance to the engineers participating in the process of learning and adopting the cloud mindset. Design cloud solutions for the internal projects of the company, delivering CloudFormation templates y setting up the delivering pipeline process.

SOA Technical Leader and Architect - Assist Systems Consultants. (March 2011 to October 2018)

Development of implementation in several projects and different platforms:

- **Alkosto:** Development of services in IBM Integration Bus that support the migration of the Magento e-commerce platform to SAP Hybris.
- **AOS SAS**: Pre-sales engineer and solution evaluator to determine the scope of different company projects. Attendance to different international events to present the company. General Bank: Installation, implementation and definition of the architecture for the execution of IBM DataPower Gateway in Panama City. Development of integrations under the proposed architecture of integration services. Post-implementation support and development of additional services against third parties. Training is done on the tool and the architecture proposed.
- **R3 Corda:** Participation in the course of blockchain in New York City, with a view to opening a partnership with the company. It is possible to have a certification as an implementer on this tool.
- **Bank Colpatria:** Definition of architecture guidelines for the new microservice scheme that they implement internally, making use of tools such as ITX. Support on implementations and external consultant for different projects within the organization. DataPower development factory where the implementation is carried out based on the specifications. Nearly 100 services have been developed under this modality.
- **TUYA card:** Installation and start-up of DataPower Gateway. Implementation architecture definition. Development of pilot service and training and delivery of knowledge to the client.
- **Experian:** Definition of the architecture and information gathering for the complete implementation of virtual DataPower on the VMWare ESX platform. After the start-up, the pilot services are implemented to carry out the validation of the proposed architecture. The training plan for this implementation is carried out.
- **CorpBanca:** Development of 30 services in IBM Integration Bus for the Motor of Payments project, Transact and of Foreign Currency Box Office. Installation and definition of architecture for the assurance of services in DataPower. Management of service integration against third parties using the proposed architecture. External DataPower Consultant. Evaluator of how to make better use of DataPower's capabilities.
- **Bank of Bogotá:** Development of implementations in the DataPower. More than 100 service virtualizations were developed within the organization. Participation in the definition of the new internal architecture within the organization. Support in the automation of deployments among different environments on the WAS platform, IBM DataPower Gateway, IBM Integration Bus WSRR and other internal components within the organization. Technical leader of the First Data migration project.
- Bank of Occident: Adjustments to the governance models of services implemented in the WSRR within the organization.
 Bank Itaú: External DataPower consultant. Evaluator on how to make better use of DataPower's capabilities. Definition of migration of services from 2 DataPower to one. Support in the administration of DataPower, such as implementation of firmware migrations, automation of backups, and various administrative tasks within the appliance.
- **Bank of Popular:** Definition of architecture, and development of the initial framework for the Implementation of FirstData project services.
- **ATH:** Implementation of different services on IBM Integration Bus.
- Senior Developer and Configuration Manager. Fenalco Presidencia Nacional (August 2009 to February 2011)

 Maintenance of applications built in JEE 5 and Oracle. Development of components for the front-end on Swing.

 Management of the configuration, versions, releases, branches and merges.
- **Project and Technology Manager. Business Logic**

(August 2007 to July 2009)

Requirement elicitation and estimates of time and money. Follow-up of tasks associated with schedules. Support in the Architecture documentation for Projects.

Development engineer. Proyectos Compartidos

(May 2006 to July 2007)

Maintenance of J2EE 1.4 applications and Swing under the RUP methodology.

Development engineer. Páginas.Net / Área WorkGroup

(December 2003 to April 2006)

Development, Assembly and Customization of Administrators for various web portals. Development of applications in. ASP, PHP, JAVA y VB.NET

System Monitor. Universidad de Los Andes

(August 2003 to November 2003)

Tutoring and Correction of Algorithmic Workshops and Object-Oriented Programming.

EDUCATION Computer and Systems Engineering

University of Los Andes, Bogotá, Colombia Graduated 2009, Minor in Management